Inventory of the Cheng Tianfang papers
Hoover Institution Archives
Cheng Tianfang papers
1935-1966
2007C3
Hoover Institution Archives
14 manuscript boxes (5.6 linear feet)
Diaries, speeches and writings, and notes relating to political conditions and education in China and Taiwan.
Cheng, Tianfang, 1899-1967.
Access
Collection is open for research.
The Hoover Institution Archives only allows access to copies of audiovisual items. To listen to sound recordings or to view videos or films during your visit, please contact the Archives at least two working days before your arrival. We will then advise you of the accessibility of the material you wish to see or hear. Please note that not all audiovisual material is immediately accessible.
Acquisition Information
Acquired by the Hoover Institution Archives in 2007.
Accruals
Materials may have been added to the collection since this finding aid was prepared. To determine if this has occurred, find the collection in Stanford University's online catalog at http://searchworks.stanford.edu/. Materials have been added to the collection if the number of boxes listed in the online catalog is larger than the number of boxes listed in this finding aid.
BiographicalNote
A Chinese politician and educator, Chieng Tianfang (1899-1967) was a Zhongguo guo min dang leader in China and Taiwan, then an émigré in the United States.
Scope and Content of Collection
Diaries, speeches and writings, and notes relating to political conditions and education in China and Taiwan.
China--Politics and government--1912-1949.; Taiwan--Politics and government--1945-1975.; Education--China.; Education--Taiwan.; Zhongguo guo min dang.
- Diaries, 1936-1966
  - 1936-1939 (Box 1)
  - 1940-1943 (Box 2)
  - 1944-1946 (Box 3)
  - 1946-1949 (Box 4)
  - 1950-1953 (Box 5)
  - 1954-1960 (Box 6)
  - 1961-1963 (Box 7)
  - 1964-1966 (Box 8)
- Writings and Related Materials, 1935-1951, undated
  - Thread-bound manuscripts, 1935-1936
    - Early diaries (six thread-bound books), 1935-1936 (Boxes 9-10)
    - Cheng Tianfang manuscript (two thread-bound books), 1935-1936 (Box 10)
  - Draft notes (two folders), undated (Box 11)
  - Letter to Chiang Kai-shek, 1951
  - By others
    - "Principle of Public Administration" by Leonard White, 1951
    - "Theory of States" by Jacobson, 1952
  - Unidentified photo, undated
  - Article digests, 1938-1945 (Box-folder 12: 1-10)
  - History notes and reading list, 1950s (Box-folder 12: 11)
  - Memoranda and address book, 1954 (Box-folder 12: 12)
  - Articles written as ambassador to Germany, 1935-1938
    - "Chinese Art Exhibition in Bonn,", 1935-1936 (Box-folder 13: 1)
    - "Eleventh World Games,", 1936 (Box-folder 13: 2)
    - "Xi'an Incident,", 1936 (Box-folder 13: 3)
    - "About America,", 1935-1938 (Box-folder 13: 4)
    - "Retrospect and Prospect of the International Situation,", 1935-1938 (Box-folder 13: 5)
    - "Nazi Party,", 1935-1938 (Box-folder 13: 6)
    - "Health and Longevity,", 1935-1938 (Box-folder 13: 7)
    - "Revolution for the Love,", 1935-1938 (Box-folder 13: 8)
    - "Visit to Rhine,", 1935-1938 (Box-folder 13: 9)
    - "Visit to Hamburg, Bremen, and Frankfurt,", 1935-1938 (Box-folder 13: 10)
    - "Eliminate the Misunderstanding between Chinese and Western Cultures by Communication,", 1935-1938 (Box-folder 13: 11)
    - "Memory of E'mei Mountain,", 1935-1938 (Box-folder 13: 12)
    - "The American Revolution and Its Impacts on the World,", 1935-1938 (Box-folder 13: 13)
    - Untitled articles, undated (Box-folder 13: 14)
- Speeches, 1939-1948
  - "Sichuan Temporary Council,", 1939 (Box-folder 14: 1)
  - The Sixth Kuomintang Congress, agenda and draft, 1945 (Box-folder 14: 2)
  - Columbia University and Yale University, 1947 (Box-folder 14: 3)
  - Foreign Policy Association and Pan-American Association Luncheon, 1947 (Box-folder 14: 4)
  - Political magazines collection, 1948 (Box-folder 14: 5)